<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hockey Rules – Section 2: Teams</title>
    <link>/nhl/section-2---teams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 2: Teams on Hockey Rules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/nhl/section-2---teams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Captain and Alternate Captain</title>
      <link>/nhl/section-2---teams/rule-6--captain-and-alternate-captains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nhl/section-2---teams/rule-6--captain-and-alternate-captains/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.1 Captain&lt;/strong&gt; - One Captain shall be appointed by each team, and he alone shall have the privilege of discussing with the Referee any questions relating to interpretation of rules which may arise during the progress of a game. He shall wear the letter “C,” approximately three inches (3&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in height and in contrasting color, in a conspicuous -position on the front of his sweater. No co-Captains are permitted. Either one Captain and no more than two Alternate Captains, or no Captain and no more than three Alternate Captains are permitted (see 6.2).
Only the Captain, when invited to do so by the Referee, shall have the privilege of discussing any point relating to the interpretation of rules. Any Captain, Alternate Captain or any player who comes off the bench and makes any protest or intervention with the officials for any purpose shall be assessed a minor penalty for unsportsmanlike conduct under Rule 39 – Abuse of Officials. Should this protest continue, he may be assessed a misconduct penalty, and if it further continues, a game misconduct penalty shall be assessed.
A complaint about a penalty is NOT a matter “relating to the interpretation of the rules” and a minor penalty shall be imposed against any Captain, Alternate Captain or any other player making such a complaint.
The Referee and Official Scorer shall be advised, prior to the start of each game, the name of the Captain and the Alternate Captains of both teams.
No playing Coach or playing Manager or goalkeeper shall be permitted to act as Captain or Alternate Captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.2 Alternate Captains&lt;/strong&gt; – If the Captain is not on the ice, an Alternate Captain on the ice shall be accorded the privileges of the Captain. Alternate Captains shall wear the letter “A” approximately three inches (3&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in height and in contrasting color, in a conspicuous position on the front of their sweaters.
Only when the Captain is not in uniform (or if there is no Captain), the Coach shall have the right to designate three Alternate Captains. This must be done prior to the start of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Starting Line-up</title>
      <link>/nhl/section-2---teams/rule-7--starting-line-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nhl/section-2---teams/rule-7--starting-line-up/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.1 Starting Line-up&lt;/strong&gt; - Prior to the start of the game, at the request of the Referee, the Manager or Coach of the visiting team is required to name the starting line-up to the Referee or Official Scorer.
Prior to the start of the game, the Manager or Coach of the home team, having been advised by the Official Scorer the names of the starting line-up of the visiting team, shall name the starting line-up of the home team. This information shall be conveyed by the Official Scorer to the Coach of the visiting team.
No change in the starting line-up of either team as given to the Official Scorer, or in the playing line-up on the ice, can be made unless reviewed and approved by the Referee prior to the start of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.2 Violation&lt;/strong&gt; - For an infraction of this rule, a bench minor penalty shall be imposed upon the offending team. This is an appeal play and must be brought to the Referee’s attention prior to the second face-off in the game. There is no penalty to the requesting team if their appeal is unsustained. The determining factor is the player or goalkeeper’s name, and not necessarily the player or goalkeeper’s number, must be correctly listed by the team.
In the event a team scores on the first shift of the game, and it is brought to the attention of the Referee by the opposing team that the team that scored did not have the correct starting line-up on the ice, the goal shall be allowed and a bench minor penalty assessed to the offending team for having an improper starting line-up. If the team that scores a goal on the first shift of the game challenges the starting lineup of the opposing team and the opposing team did not have the correct starting line-up, the scoring of the goal would nullify the bench minor penalty and no further penalties would be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Injured Players</title>
      <link>/nhl/section-2---teams/rule-8--injured-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nhl/section-2---teams/rule-8--injured-players/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.1 Injured Player&lt;/strong&gt; - When a player is injured or compelled to leave the ice during a game, he may retire from the game and be replaced by a substitute, but play must continue without the teams leaving the ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the play, if an injured player wishes to retire from the ice and be replaced by a substitute, he must do so at the players’ bench and not through any other exit leading from the rink. This is not a legal player change and therefore when a violation occurs, a bench minor penalty shall be imposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a penalized player has been injured, he may proceed to the dressing room without taking a seat on the penalty bench. If the injured player receives a minor penalty, the penalized team shall immediately put a substitute player on the penalty bench, who shall serve the penalty until such time as the injured player is able to return to the game. He would replace his teammate on the penalty bench at the next stoppage of play. If the injured player receives a major penalty, the penalized team shall place a substitute player on the penalty bench before the penalty expires and no other replacement for the penalized player shall be permitted to enter the game except from the penalty bench. For violation of this rule, a bench minor penalty shall be imposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the injured penalized player who has been replaced on the penalty bench return to his players’ bench prior to the expiration of his penalty, he shall not be eligible to play until his penalty has expired. This includes coincidental penalties when his substitute is still in the penalty box awaiting a stoppage in play. The injured player must wait until his substitute has been released from the penalty box before he is eligible to play. If, however, there is a stoppage of play prior to the expiration of his penalty, he must then replace his teammate on the penalty bench and is then eligible to return once his penalty has expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a player is injured so that he cannot continue play or go to his bench, the play shall not be stopped until the injured player’s team has secured control of the puck. If the player’s team is in control of the puck at the time of injury, play shall be stopped immediately unless his team is in a scoring position.
In the case where it is obvious that a player has sustained a serious injury, the Referee and/or Linesperson may stop the play immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When play has been stopped by the Referee or Linesperson due to an injured player, or whenever an injured player is attended to on the ice by the Trainer or medical personnel, such player must be substituted for immediately. This injured player cannot return to the ice until play has resumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When play is stopped for an injured player, the ensuing face-off shall be conducted at the face-off spot in the zone nearest the location of the puck when the play was stopped. When the injured player’s team has control of the puck in the attacking zone, the face-off shall be conducted at the nearest face-off spot in the neutral zone. When the injured player is in his defending zone and the attacking team is in possession of the puck in the attacking zone, the face-off shall be conducted at the nearest face-off spot in the defending team’s zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.2 Injured Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; - If a goalkeeper sustains an injury or becomes ill, he must be ready to resume play immediately or be replaced by a substitute goalkeeper and no additional time shall be allowed for the purpose of enabling the injured or ill goalkeeper to resume his position. The substitute goalkeeper shall be allowed a two (2) minute warm-up during all pre-season games. No warm-up shall be permitted for a substitute goalkeeper in all regular League or Playoff games.
The Referee shall report to the Commissioner for disciplinary action any delay in making a goalkeeper substitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The substitute goalkeeper shall be subject to the regular rules governing goalkeepers and shall be entitled to the same privileges.
When a substitution for the regular goalkeeper has been made, such regular goalkeeper shall not resume his position until the next stoppage of play. For a violation of the rule, a minor penalty for delay of game shall be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When play has been stopped by the Referee or Linesperson due to an injured goalkeeper, such goalkeeper must be substituted for only if he has to proceed to the players’ bench to receive medical attention. If the Trainer has come onto the ice to attend to the goalkeeper and there is no undue delay, the goalkeeper may remain in the game. However, no additional time shall be permitted by the Referee for the purpose of enabling the injured goalkeeper to resume his position (i.e. no warm-up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.3 Blood&lt;/strong&gt; – A player who is bleeding or who has visible blood on his equipment or body shall be ruled off the ice at the next stoppage of play. Such player shall not be permitted to return to play until the bleeding has been stopped and the cut or abrasion covered (if necessary). It is required that any affected equipment and/or uniform be properly decontaminated or exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
