<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hockey Rules – Section 1: Playing Area</title>
    <link>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 1: Playing Area on Hockey Rules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/nhl/section-1--playing-area/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Rink</title>
      <link>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/rule-1---rink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/rule-1---rink/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 Rink&lt;/strong&gt; - National Hockey League games shall be played on an ice surface known as the “Rink” and must adhere to the dimensions and specifications prescribed by the League and these rules. No ice markings shall be permitted except those provided for under these rules unless express written permission has been obtained from the League. On-ice logos must not interfere with any official ice markings provided for the proper playing of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interval between periods, the ice surface shall be flooded unless mutually agreed to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Dimensions&lt;/strong&gt; - The official size of the rink shall be two hundred feet (200&amp;rsquo;) long and eighty-five feet (85&amp;rsquo;) wide. The corners shall be rounded in the arc of a circle with a radius of twenty-eight feet (28&amp;rsquo;). See diagram on page iv preceding the table of contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Boards and Glass&lt;/strong&gt; - The rink shall be surrounded by a wall known as the “boards” which shall extend not less than forty inches (40&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) and not more than forty-eight inches (48&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) above the level of the ice surface. The ideal height of the boards above the ice surface shall be forty-two inches (42&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;). Except for the official markings provided for in these rules, the entire playing surface and the boards shall be white in color except the kick plate at the bottom of the boards, which shall be light yellow in color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any variations from any of the foregoing dimensions shall require official authorization by the League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boards shall be constructed in such a manner that the surface facing the ice shall be smooth and free of any obstruction or any object that could cause injury to players.
Affixed to the boards and extending vertically shall be approved safety glass extending eight feet (8’) above the boards at each end of the rink and not less than five feet (5’) along both sides of the rink. Protective glass shall be required in front of the penalty benches. The glass and gear to hold them in position shall be properly padded or protected and mounted on the boards on the side away from the playing surface including the spectator netting outlined in Rule 1.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.4 Spectator Netting&lt;/strong&gt; – Spectator netting shall be hung in the ends of the arena, of a height, type, and in a manner approved by the League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.5 Lines&lt;/strong&gt; - Eleven feet (11&amp;rsquo;) from each end of the rink and in the center of a red line two inches (2&amp;quot;) wide drawn completely across the width of the ice and continued vertically up the side of the boards, regulation goal posts and nets shall be set in such a manner as to remain stationary during the progress of a game. The red line, two inches (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) wide, between the goal posts on the ice and extended completely across the rink, shall be known as the “GOAL LINE.” In front of each goal, a “GOAL CREASE” area shall be marked by a red line two inches (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in width. The ice surface between the goals shall be divided into three zones by lines, twelve inches (12&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in width, and blue in color, drawn sixty-four feet (64&amp;rsquo;) out from the goal lines, and extended completely across the rink, parallel with the goal lines, and continued vertically up the side of the boards. (Paint code PMS 286.) Another line, twelve inches (12&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in width and red in color, drawn completely across the rink in center ice, parallel with the goal lines and continued vertically up the side of the boards, known as the “CENTER LINE.” This line shall contain regular interval markings of a uniform distinctive design, which will readily distinguish it from the two blue lines, the outer edges of which must be continuous. (Paint code PMS 186.)
&lt;strong&gt;1.6 Division of Ice Surface&lt;/strong&gt; - That portion of the ice surface in which the goal is situated shall be called the “DEFENDING ZONE” of the Team defending that goal; the central portion shall be known as the “NEUTRAL ZONE,” and the portion farthest from the defended goal as the “ATTACKING ZONE.”
&lt;strong&gt;1.7 Goal Crease / Referee Crease&lt;/strong&gt; - The goal crease shall be laid out as follows: One foot (1&amp;rsquo;) outside of each goal post a two-inch (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) line shall be painted extending four feet, six inches (4&#39;6&amp;quot;) in length. These lines shall be at right angles to the goal line. A semi-circle line six feet (6&amp;rsquo;) in radius and two inches (2&amp;quot;) in width shall be drawn using the center of the goal line as the center point and connecting both ends of the side of the crease. On the side of the crease lines, four feet (4&amp;rsquo;) from the goal line, extend a five-inch (5&amp;quot;) line into the crease. (see diagram on page iv preceding the table of contents).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal crease area shall include all the space outlined by the crease lines and extending vertically four feet (4&amp;rsquo;) to the level of the top of the goal frame. The area outlined by the crease line and the goal line shall be painted a light blue color. (Paint code PMS 298.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area inside the goal frame to the goal line shall be painted a gloss white color.
On the ice immediately in front of the Penalty Timekeeper’s seat there shall be marked in red on the ice a semi-circle of ten foot (10&amp;rsquo;) radius and two inches (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in width which shall be known as the “REFEREE’S CREASE.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.8 Goalkeeper’s Restricted Area&lt;/strong&gt; - A restricted trapezoid-shaped area behind the goal will be laid out as follows: Seven feet (7&amp;rsquo;) outside of each goal crease (eight feet (8&amp;rsquo;) from each goal post), a two-inch (2&amp;quot;) red line shall be painted extending from the goal line to a point on the end of the rink ten feet (10&amp;rsquo;) from the goal crease (eleven feet (11&amp;rsquo;) from the goal post) and continuing vertically up the kick plate (see diagram on the page iv preceding the table of contents). (Paint code PMS 186).
&lt;strong&gt;1.9 Face-off Spots and Circles&lt;/strong&gt; - A circular blue spot, twelve inches (12&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in diameter, shall be marked exactly in the center of the rink; and with this spot as a center, a circle of fifteen feet (15&amp;rsquo;) radius shall be marked with a blue line two inches (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) in width.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two red spots two feet (2&amp;rsquo;) in diameter shall be marked on the ice in the neutral zone five feet (5&amp;rsquo;) from each blue line. Within the face-off spot, draw two parallel lines three inches (3&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) from the top and bottom of the spot. The area within the two lines shall be painted red, the remainder shall be painted white. The spots shall be forty-four feet (44&amp;rsquo;) apart and each shall be a uniform distance from the adjacent boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circles shall be two inches (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) wide with a radius of fifteen feet (15&amp;rsquo;) from the center of the face-off spots. At the outer edge of both sides of each face-off circle and parallel to the goal line shall be marked two red lines, two inches (2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) wide and two feet (2&amp;rsquo;) in length and five feet seven inches (5&#39;7”) apart. One foot away from the outer edge of the face-off spot, two lines shall be drawn parallel with the side boards that shall be four feet (4&amp;rsquo;)in length and eighteen inches (18&amp;quot;) apart. Parallel to the end boards, commencing at the end of the line nearest to the face-off spot, a line shall extend two feet ten inches (2&#39;10&amp;quot;) in length. All lines shall be two inches (2&amp;quot;) in width. See diagram on page v preceding the table of contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The location of the face-off spots shall be fixed in the following manner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along a line twenty feet (20&amp;rsquo;) from each goal line and parallel to it, mark two points twenty-two feet (22&amp;rsquo;) on both sides of the straight line joining the center of the two goals. Each such point shall be the center of a face-off spot and circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.10 Ice Cleaning&lt;/strong&gt; - Aside from the normal ice resurfacing that is performed during the intermissions between each period of play, the following snow removal activities shall be performed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*(i) During each commercial time-out, the ice cleaning crew shall remove snow from the goal crease area, in front of the players’ and penalty benches and from side to side from the top of the circles to the end boards (ideally, the entire end zone from the blue lines in).*
*(ii) During the regular season, at the end of the third period in a tied game and prior to the commencement of the five minute overtime period, the entire ice surface shall be shoveled by arena personnel utilizing the same procedures as are utilized during TV time-outs.*
*(iii) During the regular season, at the end of the five minute overtime period in a tied game and prior to the commencement of the shootout, the entire ice surface shall be shoveled by arena personnel utilizing the same procedures as are utilized during TV time-outs.* 
*(iv) During overtime in the playoffs, the procedure outlined in (i) above will take place at the first stoppage of play at or following the 10:00 mark of the period. This will occur regardless as to whether or not an icing has occurred or a penalty for either team is in effect.*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific and technical guidelines for the above procedures are available from the NHL Hockey Operations Department and are distributed when updated to the arena managers as required.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Goal Posts and Nets</title>
      <link>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/rule-2--goal-posts-and-nets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/rule-2--goal-posts-and-nets/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 Goal Posts&lt;/strong&gt; - The goal posts shall be kept in position by means of flexible pegs affixed in the ice or floor. The flexible pegs shall be ten inches (10&amp;quot;) in length and yellow in color.
The goal posts shall be of approved design and material, extending vertically four feet (4&amp;rsquo;) above the surface of the ice and set six feet (6&amp;rsquo;) apart measured from the inside of the posts. A crossbar of the same material as the goal posts shall extend from the top of one post to the top of the other. See diagram on page v preceding table of contents.
The goal posts and crossbar shall be painted in red and all other exterior surfaces shall be painted in white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2 Nets&lt;/strong&gt; - There shall be attached to each goal frame a net of approved design made of white nylon cord which shall be draped in such a manner as to prevent the puck coming to rest on the outside of it, yet strung in a manner that will keep the puck in the net.
A skirt of heavy white nylon fabric or heavyweight white canvas shall be laced around the base plate of the goal frame in such a way as to protect the net from being cut or broken. This protective padding must be attached in a manner that will not restrict the puck from completely crossing the goal line. This padding must be set back six inches (6&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) from the inside of the goal post. This skirt shall not project more than one inch (1&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) above the base plate.
The frame of the goal shall be draped with a nylon mesh net so as to completely enclose the back of the frame. The knotless nylon netting shall be made of heat set, resin treatment twine (0.197 inch (5 mm) diameter) or equivalent braided twine of multifilament white nylon with an appropriate break strength of 550 to 600 pounds (250-275 kilograms). The size of the mesh shall be two and one-half inches (2½&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) (inside measurement) from each knot to each diagonal knot when fully stretched. The net shall be laced to the frame with medium white nylon cord no smaller in size than No. 21.
The thin nylon mesh netting on the top of the goal frame shall be white 12 ply, four braid construction and 62 mm inside to inside mesh. This netting will be attached with 2.2 mm clear coated white twine of Dynemma braided construction.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Benches</title>
      <link>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/rule-3--benches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nhl/section-1--playing-area/rule-3--benches/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1 Players’ Benches&lt;/strong&gt; - Each rink shall be provided with seats or benches for the use of players of both teams. The accommodations provided, including benches and doors, MUST be uniform for both teams. Such seats or benches shall have accommodation for at least fourteen (14) persons of each team. The benches shall be placed immediately alongside the ice as near to the center of the rink as possible. Two doors for each bench must be uniform in location and size and as convenient to the dressing rooms as possible.
Each players’ bench should be twenty-four feet (24&amp;rsquo;) in length and when situated in the spectator area, shall be separated from the spectators by a protective glass so as to afford the necessary protection for the players. The players’ benches shall be on the same side of the playing surface opposite the penalty bench and should be separated by a substantial distance, if possible.
Each players’ bench shall have two doors which must be uniform in location and size. (“Mirrored image benches”) All doors opening to the playing surface shall be constructed so that they swing inward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 Penalty Bench&lt;/strong&gt; - Each rink must be provided with benches or seats to be known as the “PENALTY BENCH.” These benches or seats must be capable of accommodating a total of ten persons including the OffIce Officials. Separate penalty benches shall be provided for each Team and they shall be situated on opposite sides of the Timekeeper’s area, directly across the ice from the players’ benches. The penalty bench(es) must be situated in the neutral zone. 
Each Penalty Bench shall be protected from the spectator area by means of a glass partition which shall not be less than five feet (5&amp;rsquo;) above the height of the boards.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
