<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hockey Rules – Section 4: Penalites</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 4: Penalites on Hockey Rules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Calling of Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-15--calling-of-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-15--calling-of-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.1 Calling a Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - Should an infraction of the rules which would call for a minor, major, misconduct, game misconduct or match penalty be committed by a player of the side in control of the puck, the Referee shall immediately blow his whistle and penalize the offending player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should an infraction of the rules which would call for a minor, major, misconduct, game misconduct or match penalty be committed by a player of the team not in control of the puck, the Referee shall raise his arm to signal the delayed calling of a penalty. When the team to be penalized gains control of the puck, the Referee will blow his whistle to stop play and impose the penalty on the offending player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a player, Trainer, Manager, coach or non-playing Club personnel is ejected from the game for a violation of the playing rules, that individual must vacate the players’ bench area and may not, in any manner, further participate in the game. This includes directing the team from the spectator area or by radio communications. Any violations shall be reported to the Commissioner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to Reference Tables – Table 1 – Summary of Penalties to Coaches and Non-playing Club Personnel (page 137) for a list of infractions specific to those individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.2 Calling a Minor Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; – Goal Scored - If the penalty to be imposed is a minor penalty and a goal is scored on the play by the non-offending side, the minor penalty shall not be imposed but major and match penalties shall be imposed in the normal manner regardless of whether or not a goal is scored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If two or more minor penalties were to be imposed and a goal is scored on the play by the non-offending side, the Captain of the offending team shall designate to the Referee which minor penalty(ies) will be assessed and which minor penalty will be washed out as a result of the scoring of the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.3 Calling a Double-minor Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; – Goal Scored - When the penalty to be imposed is applicable under Rule 47 for Head-butting or Rule 58 Butt-ending, Rule 60 High-sticking or Rule 62 Spearing, and a goal is scored, two minutes of the appropriate penalty will be assessed to the offending player. (This will be announced as a double-minor for the appropriate infraction and the player will serve two (2) minutes only.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.4 Calling a Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; – Short-handed Team – Goal Scored - If when a team is “short-handed” by reason of one or more minor or bench minor penalties, and the Referee signals a further minor penalty or penalties against the “short-handed” team and a goal is scored by the non-offending side before the whistle is blown, then the goal shall be allowed. The penalty or penalties signaled shall be assessed and the first of the minor penalties already being served shall automatically terminate under Rule 16 – Minor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penalties. Major and match penalties shall be imposed in the normal manner regardless of whether or not a goal is scored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should a minor or bench minor penalty be signaled against a team already short-handed by reason of a major (or match) penalty, but efore the play can be stopped to assess the minor or bench minor penalty, and a goal is scored by the non-offending side, the signaled minor or bench minor penalty shall not be imposed due to the scoring of the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should a penalty be signaled against a team already short-handed by reason of one or more minor or bench minor penalties, and the signaled penalty would result in the awarding of a penalty shot, but before the Referee can stop play to award the penalty shot, the nonoffending team scores a goal, then the signaled penalty (that would have resulted in a penalty shot) shall be assessed as a minor (doubleminor, major or match) penalty and the first of the minor penalties
already being served shall automatically terminate under Rule 16 – Minor Penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.5 Face-off Locations&lt;/strong&gt; – When players are penalized at a stoppage of play so as to result in one or more penalties being placed on the penalty time clock to one team, the ensuing face-off shall be conducted at one of the two face-off spots in the offending team’s end zone. There are only three (3) exceptions to this application:
&lt;em&gt;(i) when a penalty is assessed after the scoring of a goal – face-off at center ice;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(ii) when a penalty is assessed at the end (or start) of a period – face-off at center ice;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(iii) when the defending team is penalized and the attacking players enter the attacking zone beyond the outer edge of the end zone face-off circle –	face-off in the neutral zone (see Rule 76.2, paragraph 10);&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Minor Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-16--minor-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-16--minor-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16.1 Minor Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - For a minor penalty, any player, other than a goalkeeper, shall be ruled off the ice for two (2) minutes during which time no substitute shall be permitted. 16.2 Short-handed - “Short-handed” means that the team is below the numerical strength of its opponent on the ice at the time the goal is scored. The minor or bench minor penalty which terminates automatically is the one with the least amount of time on the clock. Thus coincident minor penalties to both Teams do not cause either side to be “short-handed” (see Rule 19 – Coincidental Penalties).
If while a team is “short-handed” by one or more minor or bench minor penalties, the opposing team scores a goal, the first of such penalties shall automatically terminate.
This rule shall also apply when a goal is awarded.
This rule does not apply when a goal is scored on a penalty shot (i.e. offending team’s penalized player(s) do not get released on the scoring of a goal on a penalty shot).
&lt;strong&gt;Minor penalty expiration criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(i) Is the team scored against short-handed?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(ii) Is the team scored against serving a minor penalty on the clock?&lt;/em&gt;
If both criteria are satisfied, the minor penalty with the least amount of time on the clock shall terminate except when coincidental penalties are being served. Refer to Reference Tables – Table 14 – Goals Scored Against a Short-handed Team (page 144).
No penalty shall expire when a goal is scored against a team on a penalty shot.
When the minor penalties of two players of the same team terminate at the same time, the Captain of that team shall designate to the Referee which of such players will return to the ice first and the Referee will instruct the Penalty Timekeeper accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16.3 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to Reference Tables – Table 2 – Summary of Minor Penalties (page 137), for a list of infractions that can result in a minor penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Bench Minor Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-17--bench-minor-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-17--bench-minor-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17.1 Bench Minor Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - A bench minor penalty involves the removal from the ice of one player of the team against which the penalty is assessed for a period of two (2) minutes. Any player except a goalkeeper of the team may be designated to serve the penalty by the Coach through the playing Captain and such player shall take his place on the penalty bench promptly and serve the penalty as if it was a minor penalty imposed upon him.
&lt;strong&gt;17.2 Short-handed&lt;/strong&gt; – see 16.2.
&lt;strong&gt;17.3 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to Reference Tables – Table 3 – Summary of Bench Minor Penalties (page 138) for a list of infractions that can result in a bench minor penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Double-minor Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-18--double-minor-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-18--double-minor-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18.1 Double-minor Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - For a double-minor penalty, any player, other than a goalkeeper, shall be ruled off the ice for four (4) minutes during which time no substitute shall be permitted.
&lt;strong&gt;18.2 Short-handed&lt;/strong&gt; – see 16.2.
When a double-minor penalty has been signaled by the Referee and the non-offending team scores during the delay, one of the minor penalties shall be washed out and the penalized player will serve the remaining two minutes of the double-minor penalty. The penalty will be announced as a double-minor penalty but only two minutes would be shown on the penalty time clock.
&lt;strong&gt;18.3 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to Reference Tables – Table 4 – Summary of Double-minor Penalties (page 139) for a list of infractions that can result in a double-minor penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Coincidental Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-19--coincidental-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-19--coincidental-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19.1 Coincidental Minor Penalties&lt;/strong&gt; - When coincidental minor penalties or coincidental minor penalties of equal duration are imposed against players of both teams, the penalized players shall all take their places on the penalty benches and such penalized players shall not leave the penalty bench until the first stoppage of play following the expiry of their respective penalties. Where goalkeepers are involved, refer to 27.1. Immediate substitution shall be made for an equal number of minor penalties or coincidental minor penalties of equal duration to each team so penalized and the penalties of the players for which substitutions have been made shall not be taken into account for the purpose of the delayed penalty rule (Rule 26 – Delayed Penalties). This rule only applies when at least one team is already serving a time penalty in the penalty box that causes them to be short-handed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one minor penalty is assessed to one player of each team at the same stoppage in play, these penalties will be served without substitution provided there are no other penalties in effect and visible on the penalty clocks. Both teams will therefore play four skaters against four skaters for the duration of the minor penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should one or both of these players (or any other players) also incur a misconduct penalty in addition to their one minor penalty, this rule shall apply and the teams would still play four skaters against four skaters (the player incurring the misconduct penalty would have to serve the entire 12 minutes – minor plus misconduct – and his team would have to place an additional player on the penalty bench to serve the minor penalty and be able to return to the ice when the minor penalty expires).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When multiple penalties are assessed to both teams, equal numbers of minor and major penalties shall be eliminated using the coincidental penalty rule and any differential in time penalties shall be served in the normal manner and displayed on the penalty time clock accordingly (see 19.5). If there is no differential in time penalties, all players will serve their allotted penalty time, but will not be released until the first stoppage of play following the expiration of their respective penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For coincidental penalties that carry over into, or are assessed during regular-season overtime, refer to 84.3, to Reference Tables – Table 17 – Penalties In Effect Prior to the Start of Overtime – Regular Season on page 160, and to Reference Tables – Table 18 – Penalties Assessed in Overtime – Regular Season on page 161.
&lt;strong&gt;19.2 Coincidental Major Penalties&lt;/strong&gt; - When coincidental major penalties or coincidental penalties of equal duration, including a major and/or a match penalty, are imposed against players of both teams, the penalized players shall all take their places on the penalty benches and such penalized players shall not leave the penalty benches until the first stoppage of play following the expiry of their respective penalties. Immediate substitutions shall be made for an equal number of major penalties, or coincidental penalties of equal duration including a major penalty to each team so penalized, and the penalties of the players for which substitutions have been made shall not be taken into account for the purpose of the delayed penalty rule, (Rule 26 – Delayed Penalties). In such situations, if one or both players have received a game misconduct in addition to their major penalties, no substitutes are required to take their places on the penalty benches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19.3 Coincidental Match Penalties&lt;/strong&gt; - When coincidental match penalties or coincidental penalties of equal duration, including a major and/or a match penalty, are imposed against players of both teams, the players with the match penalties shall be immediately removed from the game. The remaining penalized players shall not leave the penalty benches until the first stoppage of play following the expiry of their respective penalties. Immediate substitutions shall be made for an equal number of major and/or match penalties, or coincidental penalties of equal duration including a major or match penalty to each team so penalized, and the penalties of the players for which substitutions have been made shall not be taken into account for the purpose of the delayed penalty rule, (Rule 26 – Delayed Penalties).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19.4 Last Five Minutes and Overtime&lt;/strong&gt; - During the last five (5) minutes of regulation time, or at any time in overtime, when a minor penalty (or double-minor penalty) is assessed to one player of Team A, and a major (or match) penalty is assessed to one player of Team B at the same stoppage of play, the three-minute (or one-minute) differential shall be served immediately as a major penalty. This is also applicablewhen coincidental penalties are negated, leaving the aforementioned examples. In such instances, the team of the player receiving the major penalty must place the replacement player in the penalty bench prior to expiration of the penalty. In the case of a match penalty, the team must place the replacement player in the penalty bench immediately. The differential will be recorded on the penalty clock as a three (3) minute or a one (1) minute penalty (as applicable), and served in the same manner as a major penalty. This rule shall be applied regardless as to the on-ice strength of the two teams at the time the above outlined penalties are assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19.5 Applying the Coincidental Penalty Rule&lt;/strong&gt; – When multiple penalties are assessed to both teams at the same stoppage of play, the following rules are to be utilized by the Referees to determine the onice strength for both teams:
&lt;em&gt;(i) Cancel as many major and/or match penalties as possible&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(ii) Cancel as many minor, bench minor and or double-minor penalties as possible&lt;/em&gt;
Refer to Reference Tables - Table 15 – Coincidental Penalties on page 151.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Major Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-20--major-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-20--major-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.1 Major Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - For the first major penalty in any one game, the offender, except the goalkeeper, shall be ruled off the ice for five (5) minutes during which time no substitute shall be permitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one player receives a major penalty and a minor penalty at the same time, the major penalty shall be served first by the penalized player (or substitute for the goalkeeper), except under Rule 19.2 where coincidental major penalties are in effect, in which case the minor penalty will be recorded and served first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.2 Short-handed&lt;/strong&gt; – Although a major penalty does cause a team to be short-handed, the penalized player serving the major penalty does not leave the penalty bench when the opposing team scores. The player must wait for the entire major penalty to expire before he is permitted to exit the penalty bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.3 Substitution&lt;/strong&gt; – When a player has been assessed a major penalty and has been removed from the game or is injured, the offending team does not have to place a substitute player on the penalty bench immediately, but must do so at a stoppage of play prior to the expiration of the major penalty. He may then legally exit the penalty bench&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when the major penalty has expired. If the player has been assessed minor penalties in addition to the major penalty that must also be served on the penalty time clock, the offending team must place a substitute on the penalty bench immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failure to place a player on the penalty bench prior to the expiration of the major penalty will result in that team having to continue playing one player short (but not officially considered shorthanded) until the next stoppage of play. Any replacement player who enters the game other than from the penalty bench shall constitute an illegal substitution under Rule 68 – Illegal Substitution calling for a bench minor penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if the team fails to place a player on the penalty bench to return to the ice at the end of the major penalty, they continued to play short-handed but are not permitted to ice the puck as they are no longer short-handed by reason of a penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.4 Automatic Game Misconduct&lt;/strong&gt; – An automatic game misconduct shall be applied to any player who has been assessed a third major penalty in the same game.
An automatic game misconduct shall also be applicable whenever a player is assessed a major penalty for any of the infractions listed in the Reference Tables – Table 6 –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary of Major Penalties that Result in an Automatic Game Misconduct (page 139). See specific rule numbers for complete descriptions.
When a player has been assessed a major penalty for any of the infractions listed in the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference Tables – Table 7 –  Summary of Major Penalties that Result in an Automatic Game Misconduct When There is an Injury to the Face or Head (page 140) and his opponent has suffered an injury to the face or head, a game misconduct must also be assessed. See specific rule numbers for complete descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a major and automatic game misconduct are assessed, the player shall be ruled off the ice for the balance of the game, but a substitute shall be permitted to replace the player so suspended after five (5) minutes have elapsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.5 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to the Reference Tables – Table 5 – Summary of Major Penalties (page 139) for a list of the infractions that can result in a major penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for\ complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.6 On-Ice Video Review of Major Penalties&lt;/strong&gt; – Referees shall review all plays that result in the assessment of any Major Penalty (other than a Major Penalty for Fighting) for the purpose of confirming (or modifying) their original call on the ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such reviews will be conducted exclusively by the Referee(s) on the ice in consultation with other On-Ice Official(s), as appropriate, using the technology (for example, a handheld tablet or a television or computer monitor) specified in and provided pursuant to Rule 38.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication between the Situation Room and the On-Ice Officials shall be limited to contact between the appropriate Game Logger in the Situation Room and the Referee to ensure the Referee is receiving any and all video they might request, as well as the appropriate replay angles they may need to review the penalty call. There shall be no other contact or consultation between the On-Ice Official(s) and the NHL Situation Room, or with any other non-game participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Referee shall have the following options after video review of his own call: (i) confirming his original Major Penalty call; (ii) reducing his original Major Penalty call to a lesser penalty; or (iii) rescinding the original Major Penalty altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Match Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-21--match-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-21--match-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.1 Misconduct Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - In the event of misconduct penalties to any
players except the goalkeeper, the players shall be ruled off the ice for
a period of ten (10) minutes each. A substitute player is permitted to
immediately replace a player serving a misconduct penalty. A player
whose misconduct penalty has expired shall remain in the penalty box
until the next stoppage of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21.2 Short-handed&lt;/strong&gt; - A substitute player is permitted to replace thepenalized player after five (5) minutes playing time has elapsed.
The match penalty, plus any additional penalties, shall be served by a player (excluding a goalkeeper) to be designated by the Manager or Coach of the offending team through the playing Captain, such player to take his place in the penalty box immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all match penalties, a total of fifteen minutes shall be charged in the records against the offending player (five minutes on the penalty clock, plus an additional 10 minutes for being removed from the game).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the match penalty, the player shall be automatically suspended from further competition until the Commissioner has ruled on the issue. See also Rule 28 – Supplementary Discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21.3 Reports&lt;/strong&gt; - The Referee is required to report all match penalties and the surrounding circumstances to the Commissioner of the League immediately following the game in which they occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21.4 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to the Reference Tables – Table 8 – Summary of Match Penalties (page 140) for a list of the infractions that can result in (but not limited to) a match penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21.5 On-Ice Video Review of Match Penalties&lt;/strong&gt; – Referees shall review all plays that result in the assessment of any Match Penalty for the purpose of confirming (or modifying) their original call on the ice.
Such reviews will be conducted exclusively by the Referee(s) on the ice in consultation with other On-Ice Official(s), as appropriate, using the technology (for example, a handheld tablet or a television or computer monitor) specified in and provided pursuant to Rule 38.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication between the Situation Room and the On-Ice Officials shall be limited to contact between the appropriate Game Logger in the Situation Room and the Referee to ensure the Referee is receiving any and all video they might request, as well as the appropriate replay angles they may need to review the penalty call. There shall be no other contact or consultation between the On-Ice Official(s) and the NHL Situation Room, or with any other non-game participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Referee shall have the following options following such review: (i) confirming his original Match Penalty call; or (ii) reducing his original Match Penalty call to a lesser penalty for the same infraction.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Misconduct Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-22--misconduct-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-22--misconduct-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.1 Misconduct Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - In the event of misconduct penalties to any players except the goalkeeper, the players shall be ruled off the ice for a period of ten (10) minutes each. A substitute player is permitted to immediately replace a player serving a misconduct penalty. A player whose misconduct penalty has expired shall remain in the penalty box until the next stoppage of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.2 Misconduct Penalty – Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; - Should a goalkeeper on the ice incur a misconduct penalty, this penalty shall be served by another member of his team who was on the ice when the offense was committed. This player is to be designated by the Coach of the offending team through the Captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.3 Short-handed&lt;/strong&gt; – A player receiving a misconduct penalty does not cause his team to play short-handed unless he also receives a minor, major or match penalty in addition to the misconduct penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a player receives a minor penalty and a misconduct penalty at the same time, the penalized team shall immediately put a substitute player on the penalty bench and he shall serve the minor penalty without change. Should the opposing team score during the time the minor penalty is being served, the minor penalty shall terminate (unless 15.4 is applicable) and the misconduct to the originally penalized player shall start immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a player receives a major penalty and a misconduct penalty at the same time, the penalized team shall place a substitute player on the penalty bench before the major penalty expires and no replacement for the penalized player shall be permitted to enter the game except from the penalty bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.4 Reporting&lt;/strong&gt; – All misconduct penalties assessed for abuse of officials must be reported in detail to the League office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.5 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to the Reference Tables – Table 9 – Summary of Misconduct Penalties (page 141) for a list of the infractions that can result in a misconduct penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Game Misconduct Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-23--game-misconduct-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-23--game-misconduct-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.1 Game Misconduct Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - A game misconduct penalty involves the suspension of a player for the balance of the game but a substitute is permitted to replace the player removed. Ten minutes are applied in the league records to the player incurring a game misconduct penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.2 Fines and Suspensions&lt;/strong&gt; - A player incurring a game misconduct penalty shall be reported to the Commissioner who shall have full power to impose such further penalties by way of suspension or fine on the penalized player or any other player involved in the altercation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any game misconduct penalty for which a player has been assessed an automatic suspension or supplementary discipline in the form of game suspension(s) by the Commissioner shall not be taken into account when calculating the total number of offenses under this subsection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The automatic suspensions incurred under this subsection in respect to League games shall have no effect with respect to violations during Playoff games.
Any request by a Club to have a game misconduct reviewed and rescinded by the League must submit their request in writing to the Hockey Operations Department within 48 hours of the conclusion of the game in which the game misconduct was assessed. Failure to submit the written request within this time frame will automatically result in the game misconduct being upheld and no further review of the incident will be considered or entertained. This does not apply to infractions addressed under Rule 28 – Supplementary Discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.3 Fines and Suspensions&lt;/strong&gt; – General Category - In regular League games, any player who incurs a total of three (3) game misconduct penalties in the “General Category” and exclusive of other designated categories, shall be suspended for the next League game of his team. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty, the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game. For each suspension of a player or goalkeeper, his Club shall be fined one thousand dollars ($1,000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Playoff games, any player who incurs a total of two game misconduct penalties in the “General Category” shall be suspended automatically for the next Playoff game of his team. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty during the Playoffs, the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game. For each suspension of a player during Playoffs, his club shall be fined one thousand dollars ($1,000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(i)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fighting off the playing surface&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(ii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Inciting an opponent into incurring a penalty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(iii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Intervening in an altercation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(iv)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not properly tied down during an altercation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(v)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Obscene language or gestures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(vi)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Persists in continuing an altercation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(vii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Removing jersey prior to an altercation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(viii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Secondary altercation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(ix)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Third major penalty in a game&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(x)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Throwing stick outside playing area&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 53&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.4 Fines and Suspensions – Abuse of Officials Category&lt;/strong&gt; - In regular season League or Playoff games, any player who incurs a total of two (2) game misconduct penalties for abuse of officials related infractions penalized under Rule 39 - Abuse of Officials, shall be automatically suspended for his team’s next League or Playoff game. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty, the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.5 Fines and Suspensions&lt;/strong&gt; – Stick Infractions Category - In regular season League games, any player who incurs a total of two (2) game misconduct penalties for stick-related infractions in the “Stick Infractions Category”, before playing in 41 consecutive regular season League games without such penalty, shall be suspended automatically for the next regular season League game of his team. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty, the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Playoff games any player who incurs a total of two (2) game misconduct penalties in the “Stick Infractions Category”, shall be suspended automatically for the next Playoff game of his team. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty in this category during the Playoffs the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the commencement of each Stanley Cup Finals, a player will have his current “Stick Infractions Category” game misconducts removed from his current playoff record. They will remain part of his historical record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(i)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Butt-ending&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(ii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cross-checking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(iii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hooking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(iv)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slashing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 61&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(v)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spearing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.6 Fines and Suspensions – Physical Infractions Category&lt;/strong&gt; – In regular season League games, any player who incurs a total of two (2) game misconduct penalties in the “Physical Infractions Category”, before playing in 41 consecutive regular season League games without such penalty, shall be suspended automatically for the next League game of his team. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty, the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game.
In Playoff games, any player who incurs a total of two (2) game misconduct penalties in the “Physical Infractions Category” shall be suspended automatically for the next Playoff game of his team. For each subsequent game misconduct penalty in this category during the Playoffs the automatic suspension shall be increased by one game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the commencement of each Stanley Cup Finals, a player will have his current “Physical Infractions Category” game misconducts removed from his current playoff record. They will remain part of his historical record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(i)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boarding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(ii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 42&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(iii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checking from Behind&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 43&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(iv)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clipping&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(v)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elbowing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(vi)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Head-butting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(vii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 56&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(viii)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kneeing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rule 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a player has played in 41 consecutive regular League games without being assessed a major and a game misconduct in the “Physical Infractions Category”, he will have the previous game misconduct penalties removed from his current record. They will remain part of his historical record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A player’s total games played will cover a two-year time period from the date of the first game misconduct penalty for each category of infraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.7 Automatic Game Misconduct&lt;/strong&gt; – See 20.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.8 Other Infractions That Could Result in a Game Misconduct&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to the Reference Tables – Table 10 – Summary of Game Misconduct Penalties (page 142) for a list of the infractions that can result in a game misconduct penalty being assessed (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the following list of infractions can also result in a game misconduct penalty being assessed:
(i) interfering with or striking a spectator.
(ii) racial taunts or slurs
(iii) spitting on or at an opponent or spectator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any player or non-playing Club personnel who physically interferes with the spectators, becomes involved in an altercation with a spectator, or throws any object at a spectator, shall automatically incur a game misconduct penalty and the Referee shall report all such infractions to the Commissioner who shall have full power to impose such further penalty as he shall deem appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Penalty Shot</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-24--penalty-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-24--penalty-shot/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.1 Penalty Shot&lt;/strong&gt; – A penalty shot is designed to restore a scoring opportunity which was lost as a result of an infraction being committed by the offending team, based on the parameters set out in these rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.2 Procedure&lt;/strong&gt; - The Referee shall have announced over the public address system the player designated by him or selected by the team entitled to take the shot (as appropriate). He shall then place the puck on the center face-off spot and the player taking the shot will, on the instruction of the Referee (by blowing his whistle), play the puck from there and shall attempt to score on the goalkeeper. The puck must be kept in motion towards the opponent’s goal line and once it is shot, the play shall be considered complete. No goal can be scored on a rebound of any kind (an exception being the puck off the goal post or crossbar, then the goalkeeper and then directly into the goal), and any time the puck crosses the goal line or comes to a complete stop, the shot shall be considered complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lacrosse-like move whereby the puck is picked up on the blade of the stick and “whipped” into the net shall be permitted provided the puck is not raised above the height of the shoulders at any time and when released, is not carried higher than the crossbar. See also 80.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spin-o-rama type move where the player completes a 360° turn as he approaches the goal, shall not be permitted. Should a player perform such a move during the shot, the shot shall be stopped by the Referee and no goal will be the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a player designated as a goalkeeper or alternate goalkeeper  may defend against a penalty shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goalkeeper must remain in his crease until the player taking a penalty shot has touched the puck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If at the time a penalty shot is awarded, the goalkeeper of the penalized team has been removed from the ice to substitute another player, the goalkeeper shall be permitted to return to the ice before the shot is taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team against whom the penalty shot has been assessed may replace their goalkeeper to defend against the shot, however, the substitute goalkeeper is required to remain in the game until the next stoppage of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the penalty shot is being taken, players of both sides shall withdraw to the sides of the rink and in front of their own player’s bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.3 Designated Player&lt;/strong&gt; – In cases where a penalty shot has been awarded to a player specifically fouled, that player shall be designated by the Referee to take the shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all other cases where a penalty shot has been awarded, the shot shall be taken by a player selected by the Captain of the nonoffending team from the players on the ice at the time when the infraction was committed. Such selection shall be reported to the Referee and cannot be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If by reason of injury, the player designated by the Referee to take a penalty shot is unable to do so within a reasonable time, the shot may be taken by a player selected by the Captain of the non-offending team from the players on the ice when the infraction was committed. Such selection shall be reported to the Referee and cannot be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the player in respect to whom a penalty shot has been awarded commit an infraction in connection with the same play or circumstances, either before or after the shot has been awarded, he shall first be permitted to do so before being sent to the penalty bench to serve the penalty. Except when such penalty is for a game misconduct or match penalty in which case the shot shall be taken by a player selected by the Captain of the non-offending team from the players on the ice at the time when the infraction was committed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.4 Violations During the Shot&lt;/strong&gt; – Should the goalkeeper leave his crease prior to the player taking the penalty shot touches the puck, or commits any infraction, the Referee shall allow the shot to be taken. If the shot fails, he shall permit the shot to be taken over again. When an infraction worthy of a minor penalty is committed by the goalkeeperduring the shot causing it to fail, no penalty is assessed but the Referee shall permit the shot to be taken over again. Should a goalkeeper commit a second violation and the shot fails, he shall be assessed a misconduct penalty and the Referee shall permit the shot to be taken over again. A third such violation shall result in the goalkeeper being assessed a game misconduct penalty and the Referee shall permit the shot to be taken over again, against the alternate goalkeeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a major or match penalty is committed by the goalkeeper that causes the shot to fail, the Referee shall permit the shot to be taken over again and the appropriate penalties shall be assessed to the goalkeeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goalkeeper may attempt to stop the shot in any manner except by throwing his stick or any object, or by deliberately dislodging the goal, in which case a goal shall be awarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the shot, should the goalkeeper, in an attempt at making a save, dislodge the goal accidentally, the Referee shall make one of the following determinations:
(i) Award a goal if he deems the player would have scored into the area normally occupied by the net had it not been dislodged.
(ii) Allow the shot to be re-taken if he does not score or it could not be determined if the puck would have entered the area normally occupied by the net.
(iii) If the goal becomes dislodged after the puck has crossed the goal line thus ending the shot, the above determinations do not apply, the shot is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, while a penalty shot is being taken, any player, Coach or nonplaying Club personnel of the opposing team interferes with or distracts the player taking the shot and, because of such action, the shot fails, a second attempt shall be permitted. The Referee shall impose a bench minor penalty to the offending team, and if a player on the bench is responsible, a misconduct penalty on the player responsible shall be assessed. When a Coach or non-playing Club personnel is guilty of such an act, he shall be automatically suspended from the game, ordered to the dressing room and the matter will be reported to the Commissioner for possible further disciplinary action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, while the penalty shot is being taken, any player, goalkeeper, Coach or non-playing Club personnel of the team taking the shot interferes with or distracts the goalkeeper defending the shot and, because of such action, the shot is successful, the Referee shall rule no goal and shall impose a bench minor penalty to the offending team. If a player or goalkeeper on the bench is responsible, a misconduct penalty on the player or goalkeeper responsible shall be assessed. When a Coach or non-playing Club personnel is guilty of such an act, he shall be automatically suspended from the game, ordered to the dressing room and the matter will be reported to the Commissioner for possible further disciplinary action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If while the penalty shot is being taken a spectator throws any object onto the ice that in the judgment of the Referee interferes with the player taking the shot or the goalkeeper defending the shot, he shall permit the shot be taken again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, after a player’s stick has been ruled illegal, he attempts to take a penalty shot with a second stick that is also ruled illegal prior to taking the shot, the opportunity to take the shot shall be disallowed. The player shall be assessed one minor penalty for the first illegal stick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.5 Face-Off Location&lt;/strong&gt; - If a goal is scored from a penalty shot, the puck shall be faced-off at center ice. If a goal is not scored, the puck shall be faced-off at either of the end face-off spots in the zone in which the penalty shot was attempted, except when another rule dictates the face-off location should be in an alternate location, such as when the point men enter the zone beyond the outer edge of the end zone faceoff circle or when the attacking team has been penalized on the same play (see Rule 76.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.6 Results&lt;/strong&gt; - Should a goal be scored from a penalty shot, a further penalty to the offending player or goalkeeper shall not be applied unless the offense for which the penalty shot was awarded is a major, match or misconduct penalty, in which case the appropriate penalty shall be imposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the offense for which the penalty shot was awarded would normally incur a minor penalty, then regardless of the outcome of the shot, no further minor penalty shall be served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the offense for which the penalty shot was awarded was to incur a double-minor penalty, or where the offending team is assessed an additional minor penalty on the same play, the first minor penalty is not assessed since the penalty shot was awarded to restore the lost scoring opportunity. The second minor penalty would be assessed and served regardless of whether the penalty shot results in a goal. This will be announced as a double-minor penalty for the appropriate infraction and the player will serve two (2) minutes only. No penalty shall expire when a goal is scored against a team on a penalty shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should two penalty shots be awarded to the same team at the same stoppage of play (two separate infractions), only one goal can be scored or awarded at a single stoppage of play. Should the first penalty shot result in a goal, the second shot would not be taken but the appropriate penalty would be assessed and served as normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.7 Timing&lt;/strong&gt; - If the infraction upon which the penalty shot is based occurs during actual playing time, the penalty shot shall be awarded and taken immediately in the usual manner notwithstanding any delay occasioned by a slow whistle by the Referee to allow play to continue until the attacking side has lost possession of the puck to the defending side, which delay results in the expiry of the regular playing time in any period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time required for the taking of a penalty shot shall not be included in the regular playing time or overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.8 Infractions&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to the Reference Tables – Table 11 – Summary of Penalty Shots (page 143) for a list of the infractions that shall result in a penalty shot being awarded (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four (4) specific conditions that must be met in order for the Referee to award a penalty shot for a player being fouled from behind. They are:
(i) The infraction must have taken place in the neutral zone or attacking zone, (i.e. over the puck carrier’s own blue line);
(ii) The infraction must have been committed from behind;
(iii) The player in possession and control (or, in the judgment of the Referee, clearly would have obtained possession and control of the puck) must have been denied a reasonable chance to score (the fact that he got a shot off does not automatically eliminate this play from the penalty shot consideration criteria. If the infraction was from behind and he was denied a “more” reasonable scoring opportunity due to the infraction, then the penalty shot should be awarded);
(iv) The player in possession and control (or, in the judgment of the Referee, clearly would have obtained possession and control of the puck) must have had no opposing player between himself and the goalkeeper.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Awarded Goal</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-25--awarded-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-25--awarded-goals/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25.1 Awarded Goal&lt;/strong&gt; – A goal will be awarded to the attacking team when the opposing team has taken their goalkeeper off the ice and an attacking player has possession and control of the puck (or would have gained possession and control) in the neutral or attacking zone, without a defending player between himself and the opposing goal, and he is prevented from scoring as a result of an infraction committed by the defending team (see 25.3 Infractions – When Goalkeeper is Off the Ice, below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25.2 Infractions – When Goalkeeper is On the Ice&lt;/strong&gt; – A goal will be awarded when an attacking player, with an imminent scoring opportunity, is prevented from scoring as a result of a defending player or goalkeeper displacing the goal post, either deliberately or accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25.3 Infractions – When Goalkeeper is Off the Ice&lt;/strong&gt; – Refer to the Reference Tables – Table 12 – Summary of Awarded Goals (When Goalkeeper has been Removed for an Extra Attacker) (page 143) for a list of the infractions that shall result in an awarded goal when the goalkeeper has been removed for an extra attacker (see specific rule numbers for complete descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25.4 Infractions – During the Course of a Penalty Shot&lt;/strong&gt; - A goal will be awarded when a goalkeeper attempts to stop a penalty shot by throwing his stick or any other object at the player taking the shot or by dislodging the goal (either deliberately or accidentally) (see Rule 63.7).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Delayed Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-26--delayed-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-26--delayed-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26.1 Delayed Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - If a third player of any team is penalized while two players of the same team are serving penalties, the penalty time of the third player shall not commence until the penalty time of one of the two players already penalized has elapsed. The third penalized player must proceed at once to the penalty bench. He may be substituted for on the ice to keep the on-ice strength at no less than three skaters for his team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26.2 Penalty Expiration&lt;/strong&gt; - When any team has three players serving
penalties at the same time and because of the delayed penalty rule, a
substitute for the third offender is on the ice, none of the three
penalized players on the penalty bench may return to the ice until play
has stopped. When play has been stopped, the player whose penalty
has fully expired may return to the ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the play, the Penalty Timekeeper shall permit the penalized players to return to the ice, in the order of expiration of their penalties, but only when the penalized team is entitled to have more than four players on the ice. Otherwise, these players must wait until the first stoppage of play after the expiration of their penalties in order to be released from the penalty bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the penalties of two players of the same team will expire at the same time, the Captain of that team will designate to the Referee which player will return to the ice first and the Referee will instruct the Penalty Timekeeper accordingly (this is done to expedite the release of a player from the penalty bench when the opposing team scores on the power-play).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26.3 Major and Minor Penalty&lt;/strong&gt; - When a major and a minor penalty are imposed at the same time on different players of the same team, the Penalty Timekeeper shall record the minor as being the first penalty.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Goalkeeper’s Penalties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-27--goalkeepers-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-27--goalkeepers-penalties/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.1 Minor Penalty to Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; – A goalkeeper shall not be sent to the penalty bench for an offense which incurs a minor penalty, but instead, the minor penalty shall be served by another member of his team who was on the ice when the offense was committed. This player is to be designated by the Coach of the offending team through the playing Captain and such substitute shall not be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A penalized player may not serve a goalkeeper’s penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the goalkeeper is involved in coincidental penalties being assessed and as a result, his team is required to play shorthanded due to additional penalties assessed to the goalkeeper, the player designated to serve the additional time penalties assessed to the goalkeeper may be any player as designated by the Coach of the offending team through the Captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.2 Major Penalty to Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; – A goalkeeper shall not be sent to the penalty bench for an offense which incurs a major penalty, but instead, the major penalty shall be served immediately by another member of his team who was on the ice when the offense was committed. This player is to be designated by the Coach of the offending team through the Captain and such substitute shall not be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a goalkeeper is assessed a major penalty plus a game misconduct, which is coincidental with a major or match penalty to the opposing team, no player is required to serve the goalkeeper’s penalties in the penalty box, since he has been ejected from the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should a goalkeeper incur three major penalties in one game, he shall be ruled off the ice for the balance of the game and his place shall be taken by a member of his own Club, or by a regular substitute goalkeeper who is available. Such player will be allowed the goalkeeper’s full equipment. (Major penalty plus game misconduct penalty.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.3 Misconduct Penalty to Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; – Should a goalkeeper on the ice incur a misconduct penalty, this penalty shall be served by another member of his team who was on the ice when the offense was committed. This player is to be designated by the Manager or Coach of the offending team through the Captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.4 Game Misconduct Penalty to Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; – Should a goalkeeper incur a game misconduct penalty, his place will then be taken by a member of his own Club, or by a regular substitute goalkeeper who is available, and such player will be allowed the goalkeeper’s full equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.5 Match Penalty to Goalkeeper&lt;/strong&gt; – Should a goalkeeper incur a match penalty, his place will then be taken by a member of his own Club, or by a substitute goalkeeper who is available, and such player will be allowed the goalkeeper’s full equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The match penalty, and any additional penalties assessed to the goalkeeper, shall be served immediately by a member of the team on the ice when the offenses were committed. This player shall be designated by the Coach of the offending team through the Captain. However, when the match penalty is coincidental with a match or major penalty to the opposing team, no player is required to proceed to the penalty bench to serve the goalkeeper’s match penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.6 Leaving Goal Crease&lt;/strong&gt; – A minor penalty shall be imposed on a goalkeeper who leaves the immediate vicinity of his crease during an altercation. In addition, he shall be reported to the Commissioner for further disciplinary action as may be required. However, should the altercation occur in or near the goalkeeper’s crease, the Referee should direct the goalkeeper to a neutral location and not assess a penalty for leaving the immediate vicinity of the goal crease. Equally, if the goalkeeper is legitimately outside the immediate vicinity of the goal crease for the purpose of proceeding to the players’ bench to be substituted for an extra attacker, and he subsequently becomes involved in an altercation, the minor penalty for leaving the crease would not be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, during stoppages of play in the game, he must not proceed to his players’ bench for the purpose of receiving a replacement stick or equipment or repairs thereto, or due to an injury, or to receive instructions, without first obtaining permission to do so from the Referee. Otherwise, he must be replaced by the substitute goalkeeper immediately (without any delay) or be assessed a bench minor penalty for delay of game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.7 Participating in the Play Over the Center Red Line&lt;/strong&gt; - If a goalkeeper participates in the play in any manner (intentionally plays the puck or checks an opponent) when he is beyond the center red line, a minor penalty shall be imposed upon him. The position of the puck is the determining factor for the application of this rule.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Supplementary Discipline</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-28--supplementary-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-28--supplementary-discipline/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28.1 Supplementary Discipline&lt;/strong&gt; - In addition to the automatic fines and suspensions imposed under these rules, the Commissioner may, at his discretion, investigate any incident that occurs in connection with any Pre-season, Exhibition, League or Playoff game and may assess additional fines and/or suspensions for any offense committed during the course of a game or any aftermath thereof by a player, goalkeeper, Trainer, Manager, Coach or non-playing Club personnel or Club executive, whether or not such offense has been penalized by the Referee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an investigation is requested by a Club or by the League on its own initiative, it must be initiated within twenty-four (24) hours following the completion of the game in which the incident occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28.2 Pre-Season and Exhibition Games&lt;/strong&gt; - Whenever suspensions are imposed as a result of infractions occurring during pre-season and exhibition games, the Commissioner shall exercise his discretion in scheduling the suspensions to ensure that no team shall be short more players in any regular League game than it would have been had the infractions occurred in regular League games.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nhl: Signals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-29--signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/nhl/section-4--types-of-penalties/rule-29--signals/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rule #: Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Signal Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Picture&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.1: Boarding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Striking the clenched fist of one hand into the open palm of the opposite hand in front of the chest.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209165613.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.2: Butt-ending&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Moving the forearm, fist closed, under the forearm of the other hand held palm down.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209165906.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.3: Charging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rotating clenched fists around one another in front of the chest.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209170100.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.4: Checking from behind&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A forward motion of both arms, with the palms of the hands open and facing away from the body, fully extended from the chest at shoulder level.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209170527.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.5: Clipping&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Striking leg with either hand behind the knee, keeping both skates on the ice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209170602.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.6: Cross-checking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A forward and backward motion of the arms with both fists clenched, extending from the chest for a distance of about one foot.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209170739.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.7/29.8: Delayed offside/Penalty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non-whistle arm fully extended above the head. Referees us this signal for delayed penalty. (To nullify a delayed off-side, the Linesperson shall drop the arm to the side.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209170946.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.9: Delay of Game&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The non-whistle hand, palm open, is placed across the chest and then fully extended directly in front of the body.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240209171150.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.10: Elbowing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tapping either elbow with the opposite hand.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212135110.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.11: Fighting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clenched fists side-by-side in front of the chest.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212135147.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.12: Goal scored&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;d A single point directed at the goal in which the puck legally entered.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212135539.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.13: Hand Pass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;With the palm open and facing forward, a pushing motion towards the front of the body once or twice to indicate the puck was moved ahead with the hand.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212135658.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.14: Head-butting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No signal in NHL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.15: High-sticking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Holding both fists clenched, one slightly above the other (as if holding a stick) at the height of the forehead.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212140120.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.16: Holding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clasping either wrist with the other hand in front of the chest.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212140216.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.17: Holding the stick&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two stage signal involving the holding signal (29.16) followed by a signal indicating you are holding onto a stick with two hands in a normal manner.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212140437.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.18: Hooking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A tugging motion with both arms as if pulling something from in front toward the stomach.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212140925.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Icing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(a) The back Linesperson signals a possible icing by fully extending either arm over his head. The arm should remain raised until the front Linesperson either blows the whistle to indicate an icing or until the icing is washed out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212141029.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;^^&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(b) Once the icing has been completed, the back Linesperson will then point to the appropriate face-off spot and skate to it, turning backwards somewhere near the blue line and crossing his arms across his chest to indicate icing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212141221.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.20: Illegal check to the head&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Patting flat (open palm) of the non-whistle hand on this side of the head.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212141322.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.21: Interference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crossing arms stationary in front of the chest in an “X” formation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212141430.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.22: Kicking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No signal in NHL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.23: Kneeing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slapping either knee with the palm of the hand, while keeping both skates on the ice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212141614.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.24: Match penalty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No signal in NHL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.25: Misconduct&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Both hands on hips&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212142000.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.26: Penalty shot&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non-whistle arm fully extended pointing to the center ice face-off spot.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;![[Pasted image 20240212142137.png]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
